So, I recently released an AI short film
which utilized SeaArt 2.0. Reactions
were very positive, so I thank you for
that. And as promised, today we're going
to do a full like masterclass breakdown
of the film including all the various
production tips and techniques I picked
up along the way. And uh per usual for
these kinds of masterclasses, I'll go
over the time it took and roughly block
out the associated costs so you have a
good idea of how much this might cost
you if you take on a similar project.
And we're really going to hone in on
this this new workflow because I think
this is a sneak peek into the future of
AI filmmaking. All right, dim the lights
and let's go to the movies.
So, first off, if you didn't catch
Dragon Blue, don't worry about it. Uh
we're actually going to be running it
for review here in just a moment. And
this version does differ in that I
popped on Dehancer for this version.
It's kind of like a film emulation
plugin. Uh but if you want to see the
clean version, uh that is also linked
down below. On that note, grab some
popcorn and crank the sound.
They stole something from me. And I'm
going to get it back.
>> [music]
>> Neither will they.
I'll give you one chance to walk [music]
away.
I'd hoped you'd say that.
>> [music]
[music]
>> I thought I heard some rats in the
walls.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Thanks for the dance, boys.
>> [sighs]
[snorts]
>> Because you stole something from me.
I told you it wasn't for sale.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> A ninja? That'd be fun. I've never
fought a ninja before.
But the thing with ninjas is they're
mercenaries in pajamas.
And you gave me a lot of money. A lot.
You know who I am?
Then all that money is yours.
We'll square up after.
I've missed you.
I thought you weren't going to be here.
Can you take me to the bank? I owe a
ninja a lot of money. And the moral of
the story is always pay off a ninja debt
quickly. So, off the bat, look, yeah,
this is very proudly wearing its Kill
Bill influence on its sleeve. I will
totally cop to that. What's funny is
that I this isn't even the short film I
intended to make. It actually just
started as a test and I ended up having
a lot of fun, so I kind of just kept
rolling with it. And at some point I was
like, well, this is pretty Kill Bill.
But this also gave me the opportunity to
test out some of SeaDream's multilingual
capabilities and uh it definitely
delivered there. We'll talk more about
that in the production section, which uh
I guess starts now. So, mainly our tools
here are of course SeaDream 2.0, which I
was using on Dreamina. Now, I know as of
this video access is a little bit wonky.
It is coming. I do know that, but in the
meantime, there is a lot that I think
you'll be able to mine from this
workflow no matter no matter what video
generator you're using. The other major
tools I utilized for this was NanoBanana
Pro, not two. It's a very important
distinction. I'll go over that in a
little bit. And interestingly, and maybe
the biggest game changer of them all,
was Claude. Yeah, Claude, specifically
Co-work. Obviously, we round out with
the usual grab bag of like editing
software and Topaz for the upscale. So,
on the pre-production side, now if you
haven't been playing around with Claude
and well, Co-work specifically, I do
highly recommend you try it out. I know
that this like looks a little
intimidating and all. Like I just want
to I didn't write this Claude wrote
this. So, within this project, we have
everything from templates for our like
NanoBanana character designs, uh our
scene designs,
um and even our SeaArt prompts are in
here. This is all far too much obviously
to sort of break down here. So, all of
this is actually going to be in this
week's newsletter, which will be
released tomorrow. So, you'll you'll
have access to all of this stuff. Claude
also built out a full production tracker
for me such that to keep me on track.
And it also created a safety filter
guide. So, anytime that we would run
across a keyword that would get blocked,
um it was tracking that as well as
whatever substitute, you know, keyword
that we used as a token. So that, you
know, when it wrote prompts later on, it
would substitute those words in. Massive
time saver. But uh really the power with
Co-work is the fact that you can give
Claude access to a folder on your, you
know, desktop or computer and it'll keep
everything organized for you. Like
here's our character references, our
various scenes. Like I don't do this. In
fact, I mean, I'll show you what I
normally do. What I normally do is have
one folder with just a bunch of stuff
thrown in it. I mean, you can judge me,
it's fine. I'm sure I'm not alone in
this. Uh yeah, I mean, usually there's
like there's zero organization. It's
just all stuff lives here. So, I quickly
began to think of this Claude project as
kind of like my my production office
essentially. Like production and
brainstorming. Um so, you know, every
once in a while I would just tell it,
you know, go through and clean our our
folder after generating some stuff. You
know, obviously, as I'm working here,
I'm also in tandem uh working in our
next section as well. Uh but one thing I
did want to note, Claude does have a
really impressive context window. In
fact, this is all of the stuff that we
got through. Uh but, you know, as you
continue on, you will hit a point where
it starts to get pretty stupid. Uh so,
just, you know, tell it to package up a
handoff prompt um and I said your tokens
are getting lazy. Um so, it'll basically
uh save everything out to that folder on
your desktop or whatever. So, just open
up a new project, point it at your
folder, and then essentially it'll read
the handoff prompt there and and you're
back in business. So, now that we're all
organized and the home office is all set
up, uh well, it's time to generate some
reference images. For that task, uh I
ended up moving over to Luma's new agent
board feature. Um now, granted, like
these sort of agentic boards do seem to
be popping up in a number of spots.
Notably, Flora has a version of this
where you can give it kind of a number
of shots and then uh tell the agent, you
know, give me some more coverage on
these scenes. Recraft also has a version
of this that I like. Uh we're actually
going to be taking a look at that
tomorrow. So, yeah, I mean, it's been a
busy week. But I will say that I have
not pushed any of them as hard as I
pushed the Luma one. Um so, yeah, this
is essentially the project. Uh I kind of
went ham on this. There's some extra
stuff in here as well. You don't have to
go quite this nuts. But I do have to say
the Luma Canvas agent is really smart.
So, uh initially I just began actually
with just a brief um that uh I put in
via text and uh just some, you know,
shots of our character. Uh ended up
labeling her the girl uh instead of
flamethrower girl cuz she didn't have
her flamethrower. Um and just by having
like this text here, the board
essentially knows who she is. And then I
also dropped in the script so that the
board would essentially have context and
understanding of what we were creating
here. Uh and then from here actually,
this is just one of our NanoBanana
prompt templates over here. Um we'll
we'll talk about that in just a minute.
So, this is just kind of a random one.
So, initially I will admit that I was
kind of going with a spray and pray
approach here and just generating a lot
of images. Like this is kind of like the
arrival. Uh we would end up with some
stuff that, you know, is getting honing
in on what I was looking for. Uh
interesting note here by the way, there
was one that it generated up that kind
of had some characteristics of me in
there. So, I wonder if I'm so closely
associated with uh flamethrower girl at
this point that NanoBanana just randomly
throws me into things. From there,
essentially when I found something that
I'd like, I just basically drag it over
for like a collection of selects.
Initially with these uh you know, two by
two Nano Banana images, what I was doing
was actually taking them into Photoshop
and then manually cropping them till I
realized like, "Wait a minute, that's a
robot's job." So, that made my life a
lot easier. From there, it was I don't
know, kind of basically the same deal.
Talked to Claude about the script,
generate up some prompt ideas about it.
We ended up creating
our four only characters here.
And then yeah, just, you know, we just
kind of kept moving. Now, again,
sometimes you would just get some weird
stuff like our guys hanging out here
or guys with masks off. So, you know,
basically the way that we ended up
finding things was just generating by
volume. For the walk-up confrontation
scene, you know, a lot of stuff that
clearly is not going to work in here.
But again, because, you know, we're
generating so many images, eventually
we're going to find stuff that works.
And again, what's kind of cool about the
Luma canvas is that we can go through on
shots that we like and just kind of
label them with a text tool. And again,
the Luma agent knows, you know, what
shot you're talking about. What is kind
of interesting when you come out to this
like helicopter views, you can see
actually something that was intentional
on my part is, you know, this intro
section was kind of all had a blue tint
to it. Then we moved into kind of like
this warm amber kind of look. And then
that followed into the boss's office,
which kind of had a red tone. And then
ultimately ended on that cold steel. So,
yeah, a little highfalutin there. Now,
one thing I do want to note is that Nano
Banana Pro is, I mean, it's still not
good with like spatial awareness
nor spatial consistency. So, although
like in the boss's office segment, you
know, we got a lot of like accurate
versions of the boss. But you know, the
the room was kind of all over the place.
So, from there it did take a number of
rerolls after that to kind of hone in on
the look. And then from there, I ended
up pulling out enough selects that, you
know, things kind of felt like roughly
consistent at least. We did end up with
this shot, which I immediately
gravitated towards and
ended up saving this out because I
wanted at least one kind of like hero
moment in each one of the segments.
We'll We'll talk about that when we get
to the generation part. So, I would say
in total about 400 Nano Banana Pro
images
for the project. But actually more than
that because we're generating in the two
by two fashion. So, really like, you
know, four times that. Which does seem
like a lot. But you know, at the same
time, Nano Banana is pretty cheap. So, I
do think that this like spray and pray
approach does work really well. It's
just a matter of like you have to be the
one going through and, you know, picking
your selects. And especially doing your
own editing. Now, while I would love to
say that production was super smooth and
there was a, you know, direct handoff
where we did all of our images and then
brought them over to C Dance. That
wasn't the case at all. I mean, it was
completely ramshackle and I was working
Claude overtime in
organizing that folder. But you know,
once we had images,
you know, I would start rolling over to
Dreamina and heavily relying on the Omni
model. This is where you can take
multiple image references and then, you
know, add your prompt in and it kind of
ends up blending it all together. This
was a obviously a Claude written prompt.
You know, I told it what I wanted and
you know, Claude wrote this out for me.
In general, C Dance is very good. Within
one or two generations, I would pretty
much get, you know, exactly what I was
looking for. Now, that said, there it's
not perfect. But and oddly, the places
that it actually failed were kind of
interesting. Failed might not be the
case, more like struggled.
For example, actually her getting out of
the car. This one was like took way
longer than it should have. For example,
we had this shot where she gets out not
only on the wrong side of the car, but
essentially in the front seat. And then
on top of it, this happens. We had this
version, which was close, but not quite
right. And then we had this version,
which
old school body morph. I haven't seen
that in a while. So, that actually
brought me a lot of joy. Ultimately, the
trick is, here we have two drivers up
front, is as I've been saying for a
while, find the best moments from each
generation and then edit them together
afterwards. And that kind of leads us to
the first hero moment of the short,
which is, you know, the first fight
scene. So, this took in total, one, two,
three, that was a previous generation,
four. So, it was four generations in
total. Now, as has been heavily
documented, C Dance is pretty good at
doing like these crazy action sequences.
It doesn't necessarily always have a ton
of logic to it, but I mean, it moves
really fast. It will definitely do some
wacky stuff. Like that kick, that kick
is amazing.
But and you know, a lot of times there
isn't necessarily a ton of logic in
there. Like these characters just kind
of keep respawning. And as a number of
you had noted in the original release of
this, like there is this moment where
like she kind of almost like lops this
dude's head off. Something goes flying,
but then when he comes back around, he's
like, "I'm fine."
Now, I probably could have gone through
and rotoscoped that chunk of whatever
out. But you know, it just really kind
of wasn't worth it.
The other thing, if you've got a really
keen eye, you will catch some moments of
like body morphing happening here. That
[snorts] said, again, I think that
things are happening so quickly that
very rarely does anybody even notice it
when it's there. So again, I think that
you the best bet here is to generate a
couple of different fights, find the
best moments, bring them into your
editor and then just kind of treat it as
a bit of a puzzle to put together. Hero
moment number two was of course the
silhouette fight sequence. I really
wanted to do this and was initially
running into like a lot of problems
because I mean, this is this is a tough
scene. The frustrating part is that, you
know, a lot of times we would get very
close and then something like the doors
would open. Or we would get a version
like this, which is, I mean, this is
actually really good. There's even like
a third dude that shows up and I
I don't mind that at all. But then that
happens. And I was very committed to
trying to get this as a essentially a
one-er. Ultimately, the trick became
using this frame as an input image and
then using the Omni model telling it to
you create a video based on 10 seconds
before this happens. And then that's how
we ended up getting the approach of the
bad guys coming in. And then from there,
using that scene using the Omni model's
extend feature to get this scene out.
Now, I I will note that I ended up
prompting this in Chinese
mostly because I was getting a lot of
kickback on, you know, the blood
splatter. It doesn't work all the time,
but you know, sometimes that's the thing
that gets you through. Now, one thing I
do want to note is that there's always
like this slight hiccup between
extensions. Again, I was really
committed to trying to get this off as a
one-er.
So, the way that I ended up kind of
getting around that, and admittedly this
is kind of the best that I could get it,
is that I actually changed the frame
scale here to 107. So, at 100% normally,
you're going to see like a bit of a
you'll see that shift that's there. So,
the number that I found was 107. I don't
know if that will always be the case,
but it worked for here. And then I also
ended up putting a slight film dissolve
in here and then another cross dissolve
here just to kind of smooth out that
like static rigidness that often happens
when you're when you're kind of smashing
an extension together. So, best bet here
is actually put a cutaway in to hide it.
But again, I was committed to the
one-er. And then finally, rolling out to
our third hero shot,
Katana Girl in the frame of the boss's
sunglasses here. This is one where I,
you know, again, going back to the
multilingual thing, if you just prompt
in Japanese,
the character will speak in Japanese.
So, this this works across any of the
model or any of the languages that C
Dance supports. So, and yeah, you can
get back and forth as well. If she spoke
here, I would just prompt her to say
something and write it in English. Now,
I will note that the boss office scene,
while that ended up taking
three generations, I did I was running
into like weird kickback again with like
four of them where it was just like
there's a there's an image here that
is contains something that violates
community standards. What was funny was
that the image that it was giving me
grief on was actually generated by it.
It's a screenshot of, yeah, you can see
the AI up in the corner there. So, it
actually made this and said like,
"You're not allowed to use that." Look,
at the end of the day, I mean, C Dance
2.0 is very good. It is pretty much the
best video generator around right now.
But it is still AI video. So, it's going
to do like weird things. Weird and
mysterious things. It still, I mean,
it's AI video. It has a mind of its own.
For full post-production and editing, I
mean, in all honesty, pretty standard
edit in all honesty. Nothing nothing
really crazy in here beyond the fact
that, you know, subtitles. That was That
That one was new for me.
But other than that, yeah, I mean,
pretty standard. Music was generated up
in Suno.
And other than that, the only other
thing that I did that was kind of like
different was that I did take all of the
dialogue and then ran that through Adobe
Podcast Enhance and then brought it back
in. Other than that, you know, all of
the diegetic sound effects were all, you
know, still in.
So yeah, it was just essentially laid
directly on top. Now, I will say of
course, there are continuity errors. As
many had pointed out in this sequence,
the flamethrower flips around.
Surprisingly, one that nobody in the
comments caught was that when she walks
into the compound after the fight, her
sword is actually sheathed. So, got that
one past you. The point being is that
you don't go through and edit like this
without seeing every single mistake. So,
I thank you for pointing that out. I
mean, I see them, too. One that a few
people had pointed out was that at the
end when she gets into the cab, that
she's actually driving herself off.
That's actually incorrect. In Japan,
they drive on the other side of the
road. So, I was actually really nitpicky
about that one. Moving on to production
time and cost, the whole project took
about two days. Technically three
calendar days, but that's also because
I'm I'm running the YouTube channel
full-time. And this was just me. Well,
me and Claude and the Luma agent helping
out. Generation-wise, we came out to
about 85 shots generated and then
ultimately ended up using
32 shots. So,
rough shooting ratio would be 2.66.
Out of those 85 shots, I'm not sure what
like final pricing on Dreamina is going
to be. That hasn't been released yet.
So, I mean, let's just go high and
ballpark it at a dollar. So, that would
be 85 bucks. Now, I definitely went way
overboard with my Nano Banana shots. I
did end up using the 2K version, which
is cheaper. And you know, with Nano
Banana, like prices are all over the
place. So, let's just use the normal API
cost. So,
let's say I generated about 400 images.
So, that is essentially about 50 bucks.
If you are going to utilize Claude,
which is was a real lifesaver in this.
So, I do highly recommend it. A Claude
subscription in order to use co-work is
going to cost you $17 a month.
Definitely look into it. It's Claude is
really good. Suno for the music, which
would have been an additional $10. I did
run everything through Topaz. I am
actually grandfathered into the old
plan, but I think the sub cost is like
25 bucks a month now. You can also BYOU,
bring your own upscaler. And then on top
of that, of course, you know, I was
editing in Premiere. You can edit in
whatever. So, I'm not going to factor
that in. So, total cost somewhere around
$187, give or take. And look, even if we
double that cost, like you know, a rough
breakdown of essentially what this would
have cost via Gemini. So, if we were to
take this at like a Hollywood level
budget, Gemini estimated it around
$350,000.
Which I guess that's about right. Above
the line would be 35,000, below the line
180,000.
And then, you know, we had some
post-production work at $70,000.
Catering, got to have catering.
Insurance, etc. $65,000. And then I had
run it again at sort of like the
absolute indie budget level. And it came
up with about 35,000.
So, 3,000 for above the line,
18,500
for below the line including stunt
people and whatnot.
And the below line cost at 8,500. So,
yeah, I mean, it sounds about right. I
am also not a line producer. So, you
know, feel free to push back on that
price if you want. Now, of course, the
question is is like is this as good a
movie as one shot with professional
actors, a full stunt team, and a
top-notch crew? No, it isn't. But
there's also a massive cost difference
here. And look, a common criticism laid
out is that an AI film isn't a real
movie. Like you can't put this up
against a Nolan film or a Kubrick movie
or or even a Tarantino film. I fully
agree. But also, I made this for less
than $200 in two days. Just me. As for
your enjoyment of it or its artistic
merit, I mean, that's a whole other
thing. But no, it's it's not a Nolan
movie or a Scorsese movie or a Kurosawa
movie. But if you're taking the stance
that AI filmmaking will never replicate
real filmmaking, well, I mean, you kind
of have to remember that Sharknado 5
exists. That is a real movie that
actually exists and is part of the
tapestry of cinema. So, look, at the end
of the day, I had fun making this. I
hope you had fun watching it. Is it
perfect? No, it's not. But it's a good
bar of where we are right now in 2026.
And I've been at this, you know, since
it all kicked off about 3 years ago. And
I can tell you the bar for like industry
standard, I mean, it's just constantly
moving. But it also doesn't matter. You
know, make something you want to see.
Put it out in the world. Some people are
going to like it. Some people won't. But
the important part is that you don't
have to spend 5 years pitching and and
begging to make your thing anymore. You
can just do it. Anyhow, I'm going to get
off my soapbox now. I got a wrap party
to get to. As always, I thank you for
watching. My name is Tim. That's a wrap!
[screaming]
Thank you guys so much.
>> Good job.
>> you guys.
>> We love We'll see you next time.
>> next time.
>> Have a good night.